Hierarchies in Tableau give you the ability to drill down into your data.
Tableau 中的“分层结构”(Hierarchies) 可以让你深入了解数据
Tableau automatically makes hierarchies for time-based data.
Tableau 自动为基于时间的数据创建分层结构
So let's start with an example using order date.
我们先来看看一个使用“订单日期”(order date)的例子
Create a line chart showing sum of profit by order date.
创建一个按 order date 显示利润总额的折线图
A line plot is Tableau's default for time data.
折线图是 Tableau 中用于处理时间数据的默认图表
There's a little plus symbol on the order date pill now.
现在 order date 项上有一个小的加号
Let's click it and see what happens.
我们点击它看看会发生什么
What we've done here is drill down into the hierarchy starting with yearly data,
我们在这里做的是从年度数据开始深入分层结构
then grouping it by quarter.
然后按季度进行分组
As you drill down even further,
随着进一步深入
you can see the data in more granularity.
可以看到更高粒度的数据
You will notice the pills have a little minus sign in them now.
你会注意到这些项中现在有一个小小的减号
Clicking on it will go back up the hierarchy.
点击它会返回较高的分层结构
You can also remove levels of the hierarchy from
你也可以通过将这些项拖出功能区外
the plot by dragging the pill out of the shelf.
来删除某个层级
If you drill down to month,
如果你深入到“月”(Month)
and remove year and quarter,
并删除“年”(Year) 和“季度”(Quarter)
you'll see something like this.
则会看到这样的结果
It might not be what you expect here.
它可能不是我们所期望的
I expect this to show monthly profit over the four years in the data.
我想让它展示过去四年中的月收入数据
However, there is only one value for each month.
但是每个月只有一个值
Tableau is doing this because order date has been set to the discrete data type.
Tableau 之所以会这样显示 是因为 order date 被设为离散数据类型
So it's aggregating the profit values for each month, that is,
所以它合计了每个月的利润值
each value is the sum of profit for that month over the four years in the data.
也就是每个值是这四年中每个月的利润总额
However, I typically like to see this as one long line over all four years.
但是 我特别想看到全部四年的结果以一条长线展示
To change how this is being plotted,
要更改它的绘图效果
you need to convert order date to continuous data.
你需要将 order date 转换为连续数据
One way you can do this is by going to the field menu,
一个方法是前往字段菜单
clicking on the triangle,
点击三角形
and selecting convert to continuous.
并选择“转换为连续变量”(Convert to Continuous)
Once you add order date back to the visualization,
将 order date 加回到可视化后
you'll see the plus sign here again.
你会再次在这里看到加号
If you click it twice,
如果你双击它
you'll get right back down to see the order date by month.
则会在下面看到按月排布的 order date
But this time, you'll see it for every month in the dataset.
但这次 你会看到数据集中的每个月
Tableau created the hierarchy from
Tableau 自动从日期创建了分层结构 00:01:43,200 --&gt; 00:01:46,019 而你也可以创建自己的分层结构
For example, each value in subcategory belongs to one category in the superstore dataset.
例如 子类别中的每个值属于 superstore 数据集中的一个类别
This means that a record with the subcategory value,
这意味着具有子类别值的记录 如 bookcases
bookcases, always has a category value, furniture.
始终有一个类别值 furniture
However, Tableau doesn't recognize this as a hierarchy.
但是 Tableau 并不将此视为分层结构
So we can make a manual one.
那么我们可以手动创建一个
You can do this easily by dragging subcategory onto category.
你可以轻松地将子类别拖放到类别上来实现
Then you can name the hierarchy and I'll name it, products.
然后你可以命名此分层结构 我将其命名为 products
It shows up on the left and you can drag it in the shelves just like a normal field.
它显示在左边 你可以将它拖放到功能区上 就像拖放普通字段一样
But, now, it starts with category with a plus sign and you can drill down to subcategory.
但是现在 它变成了带加号的类别 （这表明）你可以深入到它的子类别